# Begum G. Vernon

# Front-end Web Developer

### **PROFILE**

An experienced Front-end Developer with a unique background as a former basketball player with 14 years of expertise. Proficient in crafting mobile-friendly web projects through the synergy of UI design, ReactJS, with a sharp eye for identifying opportunities to elevate front-end design and enhance the user experience in any platform (UX).

### **CONTACT**

Tustin, CA 949-632-5720 begum.vernong@gmail.com

My Portfolio

LinkedIn

#### **EDUCATION**

**Skillcrush,** Front-end Developer, (Sep 2022 - Apr 2023)

MBA - Southern States University, Business Administration (2019 - 2022) B.A. Dokuz Eylul University, Physical

Education Teacher (2010 - 2014)

### **DEVELOPER SKILLS**

HTML5/CSS3

SaaS

JavaScript

React

JSX

ES<sub>6</sub>

APIs

UI/UX Design

Responsive Web Design

WordPress

JIRA

Git/GitHub

Version Control

Media Queries

Managing Data Flow

#### **TECH STACK**

Chrome DevTools GitHub Pages Adobe Creative Suite

## **DEVELOPER PROJECTS**

• **Guess The Word** - Players need to enter one letter at a time to guess the word and have only 8 chances before showing the answer and skipping to the next one.

Tools used: CSS, HTML, APIs, DOM Manipulation, Vanilla JavaScript

 Zero-Waste Recipe- A Responsive Website gives you recipes based on the ingredients that you already have at home, eliminating food waste!

Tools used: VanillaJS, APIs, SaaS, ES6, DOM Manupilation, CSS3, BEM

• **Sticky Notes** - It is a single-page application that helps users enter multiple notes and customize them.

**Tools used:** React, JSX, ES6, Managing Data Flow, DOM Manipulation.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Frontend Developer**

Tustin, CA

Freelance

Dec 2022 - Present

- Developed UI using React, HTML, APIs, CSS3, and JavaScript by building, auditing, and debugging responsive web applications to increase site engagement and enhance user experience.
- Design and implement new user stories for clients using CMS technologies such as WordPress, resulting in improved usability to deliver the best user experience.
- Verified the application to work in any environment by testing, troubleshooting, and code review prior to deployment.

# Office Manager Global Dental Group

Mission Viejo, CA Aug 2020 - Present

- Manage day-to-day operations; including the coordination of schedules for 4 dental assistants, 1 attending dentist, and several patients.
- Provided guidance and trained the staff accordance with dental policies and management for the office rules.
- Manage the hiring and ongoing performance of staff and create onboarding plans for new hires.
- Finding the best trends in the industry and used the most efficient tools for the proper work,

# **Sales Marketing Manager**

Orange, CA

Style and Fix

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

- Managed and coordinated sales and marketing activities for a company and oversaw sales, marketing and advertising staff.
- Researched and developed marketing opportunities and plans, understood consumer requirements increasing sales by %20.

# **Physical Education Teacher**

Izmir, TR Aug 2017 - Jun 2018

Ozel Saygin College

 Created lesson plans and delivered instruction to middle school students, using team sports to promote a competitive desire and improvise students' athletic skills.

# **Professional Basketball Player**

Izmir, TR

Usak Anadolu 64(last game season)

Jan 2002 - May 2016

- Managed time effectively while traveling for games, attending practice throughout my professional playing career in Turkiye for 14 years.
- Attended 2 Turkiye Championship Tournaments in the youth team in 2008-2009 and 2009-2010.